{
  "results": [
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the real name of Iron Man?",
      "correct_answer": "Tony Stark",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Steve Rogers", "Bruce Banner", "Peter Parker"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the director of 'Avengers: Endgame'?",
      "correct_answer": "Anthony Russo and Joe Russo",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Joss Whedon", "James Gunn", "Taika Waititi"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which Infinity Stone is housed in Vision's forehead?",
      "correct_answer": "Mind Stone",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Power Stone", "Reality Stone", "Space Stone"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is Black Widow's best friend and fellow spy?",
      "correct_answer": "Hawkeye",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Falcon", "War Machine", "Winter Soldier"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of Thor's hammer?",
      "correct_answer": "Mjolnir",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Stormbreaker", "Gungnir", "Hofund"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the main villain in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
      "correct_answer": "Ronan the Accuser",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Thanos", "Loki", "Ego the Living Planet"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which actor portrays the character Captain America?",
      "correct_answer": "Chris Evans",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Chris Hemsworth", "Robert Downey Jr.", "Mark Ruffalo"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of Doctor Strange's mentor?",
      "correct_answer": "The Ancient One",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Wong", "Baron Mordo", "The Collector"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie marks the first appearance of Black Panther in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "correct_answer": "Captain America: Civil War",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Avengers: Age of Ultron", "Iron Man 2", "Thor: Ragnarok"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is Gamora's adopted father?",
      "correct_answer": "Thanos",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Ego the Living Planet", "Ronan the Accuser", "Yondu Udonta"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which Infinity Stone does Doctor Strange possess?",
      "correct_answer": "Time Stone",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Mind Stone", "Soul Stone", "Power Stone"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of Ant-Man's alter ego?",
      "correct_answer": "Scott Lang",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Hank Pym", "Darren Cross", "Hope van Dyne"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the main villain in 'Thor: Ragnarok'?",
      "correct_answer": "Hela",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Loki", "The Grandmaster", "Surtur"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which actor portrays the character Loki?",
      "correct_answer": "Tom Hiddleston",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Chris Hemsworth", "Mark Ruffalo", "Chris Pratt"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In 'Captain Marvel', what is the name of Carol Danvers' cat?",
      "correct_answer": "Goose",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Tiger", "Simba", "Whiskers"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the love interest of Peter Parker in the 'Spider-Man: Homecoming' movie?",
      "correct_answer": "Liz Allan",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Mary Jane Watson", "Gwen Stacy", "Betty Brant"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie features the character Valkyrie?",
      "correct_answer": "Thor: Ragnarok",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2", "Avengers: Infinity War", "Black Panther"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the leader of the Ravagers in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
      "correct_answer": "Yondu Udonta",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Star-Lord", "Rocket Raccoon", "Gamora"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe wields the power of the Tesseract?",
      "correct_answer": "Captain Marvel",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Black Widow", "Scarlet Witch", "Captain America"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the kingdom ruled by Black Panther?",
      "correct_answer": "Wakanda",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Asgard", "Sokovia", "Latveria"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the leader of the Guardians of the Galaxy?",
      "correct_answer": "Star-Lord",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Rocket Raccoon", "Groot", "Gamora"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In 'Avengers: Infinity War', who sacrifices herself to save Vision?",
      "correct_answer": "Scarlet Witch",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Black Widow", "Gamora", "Nebula"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the real name of Black Widow?",
      "correct_answer": "Natasha Romanoff",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Wanda Maximoff", "Hope van Dyne", "Jessica Jones"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie marks the first appearance of Spider-Man in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "correct_answer": "Captain America: Civil War",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Iron Man 3", "The Avengers", "Doctor Strange"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the leader of the Dora Milaje in 'Black Panther'?",
      "correct_answer": "Okoye",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Nakia", "Shuri", "Ramonda"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the planet where the Soul Stone is located?",
      "correct_answer": "Vormir",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Xandar", "Sakaar", "Knowhere"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which character is known as the God of Mischief?",
      "correct_answer": "Loki",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Thor", "Hawkeye", "Black Widow"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In 'Avengers: Endgame', what is the name of Thor's new home?",
      "correct_answer": "New Asgard",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Asgardia", "Valhalla", "Olympus"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the main antagonist in 'Captain America: The Winter Soldier'?",
      "correct_answer": "The Winter Soldier",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Red Skull", "Baron Zemo", "Crossbones"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of Thor's home planet?",
      "correct_answer": "Asgard",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Vanaheim", "Nidavellir", "Svartalfheim"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie features the character Bucky Barnes as the Winter Soldier?",
      "correct_answer": "Captain America: The Winter Soldier",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Avengers: Age of Ultron", "Captain America: Civil War", "Avengers: Infinity War"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the main antagonist in 'Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2'?",
      "correct_answer": "Ego the Living Planet",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Thanos", "Ronan the Accuser", "The Collector"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the organization that Nick Fury is the director of?",
      "correct_answer": "S.H.I.E.L.D.",
      "incorrect_answers": ["H.Y.D.R.A.", "A.I.M.", "S.T.R.I.K.E."]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the love interest of Tony Stark in the 'Iron Man' movies?",
      "correct_answer": "Pepper Potts",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Natasha Romanoff", "Jane Foster", "Peggy Carter"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which character wields the power of the Allfather in 'Thor' and 'Thor: The Dark World'?",
      "correct_answer": "Odin",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Frigga", "Loki", "Heimdall"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the villainous alien race in 'The Avengers'?",
      "correct_answer": "Chitauri",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Sakaarans", "Kree", "Skrulls"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the love interest of Thor in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "correct_answer": "Jane Foster",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Sif", "Valkyrie", "Hela"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the organization that Peter Quill (Star-Lord) is a member of?",
      "correct_answer": "The Ravagers",
      "incorrect_answers": ["The Nova Corps", "The Sovereign", "The Watchers"]
    },
    {
     "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which actor portrays the character Nick Fury?",
      "correct_answer": "Samuel L. Jackson",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Robert Downey Jr.", "Chris Evans", "Mark Ruffalo"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In 'Avengers: Age of Ultron', who creates the artificial intelligence known as Ultron?",
      "correct_answer": "Tony Stark / Iron Man",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Bruce Banner / Hulk", "Thor", "Hank Pym / Ant-Man"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the real name of the superhero known as Black Widow?",
      "correct_answer": "Natasha Romanoff",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Wanda Maximoff", "Hope van Dyne", "Maria Hill"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the leader of the Asgardian gods in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "correct_answer": "Odin",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Thor", "Loki", "Frigga"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie features the character Natasha Romanoff / Black Widow?",
      "correct_answer": "Iron Man 2",
      "incorrect_answers": ["The Incredible Hulk", "Thor", "Captain America: The First Avenger"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of the powerful alien artifact featured in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
      "correct_answer": "The Orb",
      "incorrect_answers": ["The Tesseract", "The Aether", "The Eye of Agamotto"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the leader of the Nova Corps in 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?",
      "correct_answer": "Nova Prime Irani Rael",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Nova Prime Rhomann Dey", "Nova Prime Adora", "Nova Prime Ayesha"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What is the name of Tony Stark's AI assistant in the Iron Man movies?",
      "correct_answer": "J.A.R.V.I.S.",
      "incorrect_answers": ["F.R.I.D.A.Y.", "H.O.M.E.R.", "S.A.M.A.N.T.H.A."]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Who is the main villain in 'Thor: The Dark World'?",
      "correct_answer": "Malekith",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Loki", "Hela", "The Grandmaster"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In 'Ant-Man',what is the name of the scientist who invents the Pym Particles?",
      "correct_answer": "Hank Pym",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Scott Lang", "Bill Foster", "Erik Selvig"]
    },
    {
      "category": "Marvel Cinematic Universe",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which movie marks the first appearance of the character T'Challa / Black Panther?",
      "correct_answer": "Captain America: Civil War",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Avengers: Age of Ultron", "Black Panther", "Thor: Ragnarok"]
    }
  ]
}
